sffirecu.org 2010-06-16

# SF Fire Credit Union : Your Privacy Rights

## Your Privacy Rights

### Member Privacy and Security are Paramount at SF Fire Credit Union

San Francisco Fire Credit Union does not sell our membership list to marketers or any other outside source. Your business is safe and secure and your privacy is of the utmost importance to the Credit Union.

### Information Security

> We operate secure data networks protected by industry standard firewalls, encryption and password protection. The company enforces security procedures to protect confidential information from loss, misuse or alteration.

### Privacy Disclosure

We care about your privacy and recognize our responsibility to keep the information you provide us secure and confidential. Along with protecting your financial assets, protecting your privacy is our top priority. Our privacy policy is designed to do just that. This policy is provided to you as required by law. Please read it carefully and keep it for your records.

#### Protecting Your Privacy

Our Privacy Policy explains how we protect the privacy of your personal information. It also explains certain situations where we release information about you to third parties, such as to maintain your account or other circumstances as required or permitted by law.

As long as you maintain a relationship with us, you will receive notice of our Privacy Policy as the law requires. If our information collecting or sharing practices change, we will provide you with a revised Privacy Policy. If you have a joint account with someone else or are a co-borrower, please give a copy of this Privacy Policy to them to ensure that each of you is aware of our policy and your options. Our Privacy Policy is always available upon request.

#### Confidentiality and Security

We restrict access to non-public personal information about you to those employees who need to know that information to provide products or services to you. We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards that comply with State and Federal Regulations to guard your non-public personal information.

#### Scope of Our Policy

Our Privacy Policy governs Member Information which is defined as personally identifiable information about a member or their relationship with us. The policy applies to individuals who obtain products or services from us for personal, family or household purposes. Our Privacy Policy applies to member information obtained by San Francisco Fire Credit Union.

[[Top of Page]](https://web.archive.org/about-us/privacy-and-security#top)

#### Information Obtained for Your Benefit

We obtain information about you that we believe will be necessary or useful in processing or servicing your savings and loan accounts. Your information also enables us to provide products, services and other opportunities that we think will be of interest to you. We obtain the following types of Member Information:

  * Information you provide on your loan application or that you provide to us verbally or in writing
  * Information about your transactions with the Credit Union, or affiliates and other third parties
  * Information from consumer reporting agencies
  * Information we receive from other third parties

#### Who May Receive your Information

**Information sharing with our affiliated companies**

At this time we do not have any business relationships with affiliated companies.

**Information sharing with nonaffiliated third parties**

To inform you of product and service opportunities that may be of interest to you, we might share the following types of Member Information that we obtain about you as described in this policy, with nonaffiliated third parties:

  * Information about your identity
  * Information about your transactions or experiences with us
  * Information we receive from other third parties

**Companies who may receive this information include:**

  * Financial service providers, such as credit card issuers, insurance companies and mortgage companies
  * Non-financial companies, including check printers and mailing services

[[Top of Page]](https://web.archive.org/about-us/privacy-and-security#top)

#### Information Sharing with Companies that Perform Services on Our Behalf

We may share all of the types of member information we obtain about you, as described in this policy, with companies that perform marketing services on our behalf or with other financial institutions with whom we have joint marketing arrangements, as permitted by law. All of these companies are obligated to keep the information we provide to them confidential and to use the information only to provide the services we have asked them to perform for us.

#### Information Sharing in Other Situations

We may share all the types of member information that we obtain about you in other legally permitted situations:

  * If we have your consent to a disclosure for a specific purpose
  * To complete your transaction and maintain your account, such as recording deeds of trusts and mortgages in public record
  * In response to a subpoena, a fraud investigation or other legal process
  * To credit bureaus or similar reporting agencies and with others who ask for credit references in accordance with customary business practices
  * To regulatory agencies and auditors
  * To another financial institution or entity that purchases your loan or account, or if we sell or merge parts of our business
  * To another company that we hire to collect on your account
  * To affiliates, investors, servicers, rating agencies, mortgage insurers, due diligence firms and others in connection with loan sales and securitizations

#### Our Former Members

Should our member relationship end, this Privacy Policy will continue to apply to member Information we obtained about you.

#### Maintenance of Accurate Information

We strive to keep records of member information about you accurate and up to date. When you notify us of an error, we will update or correct any erroneous information.

#### Children’s Online Privacy

The law requires parental consent to collect or use information from a child under 13 years of age. If you are a child under 18 years of age, please show this to your parents, and do not use the online services of this institution without disclosure to parents and verifiable parental consent pursuant to the requirements of the [Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act Rule](http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/privacyinitiatives/childrens.html) (COPPA Rule).

**Alternate Link:** the Federal Trade Commission’s website was hacked on July 7, 2009 and has been experiencing problems. [Here is an alternate link](http://www.coppa.org/coppa.htm) to the COPPA legislation.

[[Top of Page]](https://web.archive.org/about-us/privacy-and-security#top)

April 25, 2006
